Guide to the Exhibitions Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Exhibitions Collection
1867-1933
MS 893
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.5
An artificial collection of publications and reports from major international exhibitions, 1867-1904. The Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition, 1876, is a major component of the collection.
Arrangement
Arranged by exhibit.
Scope and Contents
The largest part of the Exhibitions Collection is made up of catalogues from the Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition of 1876. Although the set is not complete, the catalogues provide a wide overview of the exhibits. They are of two kinds: those on individual industries, crafts and professions, and those for the national exhibits issued by the participating countries. In addition there are pamphlets documenting the organization of the exhibition, with reports by the executive and planning committees (1872-1875), and some official guides and lists of awards. Reports of the Women's Centennial Association of America (1873-1875) describe the activities of women's groups which were formed to help celebrate the Centennial.
Fourteen foreign countries are represented here with catalogues describing their exhibits. These are: Argentina, Australia, Austria, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, France, Japan, Netherlands, Portugal, Russia, Spain, Sweden and Switzerland. The United States entries are divided by states. There are also catalogues for exhibits by several national agencies, among them the U.S. Corps of Engineers and the Army Medical Museum.
Miscellaneous catalogues from other world exhibitions (1873-1893) make up the remainder of the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Exhibitions -- Guidebooks; Exhibitions; Popular culture; Science; Centennial Exhibition ( 1876 Philadelphia, Pa.); Century of Progress International Exposition ( 1933-1934 Chicago, Ill.); Exposition Industrial del Estado de Mʹexico, 2nd: -- Toluca, Mexico -- 1902; Exposition universelle de 1867 à Paris; Exposition universelle ( 1900 Paris, France); Exposition universelle de 1878 ( Paris, France); Louisiana Purchase Exposition ( 1904 Saint Louis, Mo.); Panama-Pacific International Exposition ( 1915 San Francisco, Calif.); Pan-American Exposition ( 1901 Buffalo, N.Y.); Vienna International Exhibition ( 1873); World's Columbian Exposition ( 1893 Chicago, Ill.); World's Industrial and Cotton Centennial Exposition ( 1884-1885 New Orleans, La.)
- PHILADELPHIA CENTENNIAL EXHIBITION, 1876, 1872-1878; Series I; 3.25 linear feet (8 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Unbound Volumes is grouped into two parts: 1. Reports on plans for the exhibition and reports and awards for special fields. 2. Catalogues of participating countries arranged alphabetically by country.
  Bound Volumes consists of twelve bound volumes containing catalogues issued by participating countries and individual states of the United States. These collections do not seem to be grouped according to any discernable pattern, and in order to provide access to the volumes, we have listed the titles of the catalogues alphabetically by country and have indicated box and volume number in the margin.
  - Unbound Volumes
    - Official bulletins and catalogues
      - The centennial of American Independence. International Exhibition of 1876. (Philadelphia: Porter & Coates), 1875
        - Fourth revised edition., 1876 (Box 1)
      - International Exhibition company. Official Bulletin of the International Exhibition, (main Building, Centennial Grounds), Fairmount Park, Philadelphia. (Philadelphia: Exhibition Publishing Co.)
        - Number 1, 1877 January (Box 1)
        - Number 2, 1877 February (Box 1)
        - Number 3, 1877 March (Box 1)
      - United States Centennial Commission. International Exhibition, 1876. Official Catalogues, Department of Art. (Philadelphia: John R. Nagle & Co.) (Box 1)
    - Reports [Published in Brussels]
      - Beco, Jean. Rapport sur l'état des industries du zinc du plomb & du cuivre aux États-Unis d'Amérique. Première partie., 1877 (Box 1)
      - Beco, Jean. Rapport sur l'industrie du zinc, du cuivre & du plomb aux États-Unis d'Amérique. Deuxième partie., 1877 (Box 1)
      - Bertrand, Nestor. Rapport sur l'éducation & les sciences, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Debaisieux, Dr. Rapport sur la partie médicale de 1'exposition et sur l'enseignement de la médecine & de l'art dentaire aux États-Unis présenté à monsieur le ministre de l'intérieur, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Deby, Julien. Rapport sur l'industrie sidérurgique aux États-Unis au point de vue des intérêts commerciaux de la Belgique, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Dewilde, P. Rapport sur le groupe III (département II) manufactures - produits chimiques, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Duhayon, Félix. Rapport sur le groupe X: dentelles, broderies, articles de vêtement, etc., etc., 1877 (Box 1)
      - Eggermont, I. Rapport sur l'exposition universelle, 1877 (Box 1)
      - de Philadelphie au point de vue du commerce & de l'industrie belges, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Fils, Théodore Sneyers. Rapport sur le groupe VII (mobilier), 1877 (Box 1)
      - Jonas, Achilee. Rapport sur la parfumerie, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Jonas, Achille. Rapport sur la pharmacie, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Jottrand, Achille. Rapport sur les machines de mines, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Lesne, M. Rapport sur le groupe XVI (classes 265 à 270, département II du catalogue) armements militaires, marine, ordonnance, armes à feu et ustensiles de chasse, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Marlin, Paul. Rapport sur les classes 258 à 264, papiers de toute espèce, à écrire, d'impression, d'enveloppes, d'emballage, à sacs, à registres, de journal, à obligations et titres, à réglure, etc.; cartons et cartonnages; papiers de tentures; fournitures de bureau, enveloppes, crayons, encriers, etc.; cartes à jouer, reliures, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Marlin, Paul. Rapport sur les classes 633 et 652, cuirs, peaux, fourrures, machines à travailler le cuir, graisses, lard, huiles, ivoire, os et colle, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Marlin, Paul. Rapport sur les classes 658 et 661 (département VI), amidon et produits similaires, pain, biscuits et autres produits de la boulangerie et de la patisserie, 1877 (Box 1)
      - Müllender, Alph. Rapport sur l'industrie laiére, 1877 (Box 2)
      - Piret, Arthur. Rapport sur les groupes V & VI [la tannerie américaine et l'exposition belge à Philadelphie], 1877 (Box 2)
      - Van Bruyssel, Ernest. Rapport sur l'exposition Internationale Philadelphie, 1877 (Box 2)
    - Reports concerning plans for the Exhibition
      General
      See also: box 15, folder 34
      - The Centenary of American Independence. A Plan for the Celebration of the Fourth Day of July, 1876. (Philadelphia: Collins, Printer), 1873 (Box 2)
      - The International Exhibition of 1876, a National Celebration. What Has Already Been Done by Congress and the Executive. Present Condition and Immediate Wants. Office of the United States Centennial Commission., Circa 1874 (Box 2)
      - Meeting of the Executive Committee of the United States Centennial Commission, Philadelphia, 1872 August (Box 2)
      - The National Centennial. The International Exhibition of 1876. Message of the President of the United States to Congress, Transmitting the Third Report of the United States Centennial Commission on the Progress of the Work Intrusted to It Under Acts of Congress Providing for a National Celebration, by an International Exhibition and Commemorative Ceremonies, of the One Hundredth Anniversary of the United States, to be Held at Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, in the Year 1876, Embracing Reports on the Vienna Exhibition of 1873. (Washington: Government Printing Office), 1874 (Box 2)
      - Reports of the Executive Committee of the United States Centennial Commission (Philadelphia), 1874 May 20, 1876 May (Box 2)
      - The United States International Exhibition. The Organization, the Work Proposed, the Work Already Done. (Philadelphia: Dreyer, Simpson & Co.), Circa 1875 (Box 2)
      - Women's groups
        - Constitution and By-Laws of the Women's Centennial Association of America (Philadelphia: Wm. Mann, Printer), 1873 (Box 2)
        - First Annual Report of the Women's Centennial Executive Committee (Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott & Co.), 1874 February 16 (Box 2)
        - Second Annual Report of the Women's Centennial Executive Committee (Philadelphia: Thomas S. Dando), 1875 March 15 (Box 2)
    - Reports and awards [Francis A. Walker, ed. Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott & Co.]
      - Awards on National, State, and Other Collective Exhibits. International Rifle Matches. International Rowing Regatta. International Yacht Regatta., 1878 (Box 2)
      - Journal of the Proceedings of the United States Centennial Commission at Philadelphia, Philadelphia, E.C. Markley & Sons, 1872 (Box 2A)
      - Group II. Pottery, Glass, Artificial Stone, etc., 1877 (Box 3)
      - Group VI. Timber, Worked Lumber, Parts of Buildings, Forestry, 1877 (Box 3)
      - Group VII. Furniture, Upholstery, Wooden-Ware, Baskets, etc., 1877 (Box 3)
      - Group XII. Jewelery, Watches, Silver-Ware, Bronzes, etc., 1877 (Box 3)
      - Group XXVIII. Educational Systems, Methods, and Libraries, 1878 (Box 3)
      - Group XXIX. Tillage and General Management, Garden Tools, Accessories of Gardening, Garden Designing, Construction and Management, 1878 (Box 3)
      - Group XXX. Horses. Group XXXI. Cattle. Group XXXII. Sheep. Group XXXIII. Swine. Group XXXIV. Dogs. Group XXXV. Poultry., 1877 (Box 3)
      - Group XXXVI. Pomology, 1877 (Box 3)
    - Catalogues by locality
      See also: box 16, folder 37
      - The Empire of Brazil at the Universal Exhibition of 1876 in Philadelphia (Rio de Janeiro: Imperial Instituto Artistico) (Box 3)
      - Bailey, L.W. and Jack, Edward. The Woods and Minerals of New Brunswick, being a Descriptive Catalogue of the Trees, Shrubs, Rocks and Minerals of the Province, Available for Economic Purposes (Fredericton, N.B.), 1876 (Box 4)
      - Report of the Canadian Commission at the International Exhibition of Philadelphia, 1876 (Ottawa), 1877 (Box 4)
      - Catalogue of the Chilean Exhibition at the Centenary of Philadelphia (Valparaiso: Mercurio Printing Office), 1876 (Box 4)
      - Exposition Universelle de Philadelphie (1876), catalogue du cercle de la librairie de l'imprimerie et des industries qui s'y rattachent (Paris: Cercle de la Librairie) (Box 4)
      - Thomson, Robert. A Descriptive Catalogue of the Collection Sent from the Island of Jamaica to the Centennial Exhibition in 1876 at Philadelphia (Kingston: Henderson, MacDoguall & Co.) (Box 4)
      - Catalogue of the Collective Exposition at the Centennial Exhibition in 1876 at Philadelphia, of the Netherlands Booksellers' Association. Specimens of Publications of the Last Years, Including Schoolbooks, Newspapers and Periodicals (Amsterdam) (Box 4)
      - Official Catalogue of the Peruvian Section, Main Building, International Exhibition at Philadelphia (New York: Gresham & Dawson), 1876 (Box 4)
      - Malheiro, Lourenço and Sequeira, P.V. Da Costa. International Exhibition, 1876, Philadelphia. Descriptive Catalogue. Department I. Mining & Metallurgy, Circa 1876 (Box 4)
      - Philadelphia Exhibition of 1876. The National Printing Office at Lisbon, an Historical and Statistical Notice with the Catalogue of the Products Exhibited (Lisbon: National Printing Office) (Box 4)
      - Portugal. International Exhibition, 1876. Philadelphia. Catalogues: Agriculture and Colonies, Circa 1876 (Box 4)
      - List of Fossils Selected from the Main Collection in the Museum of the Mining School at St. Petersburg, Russia, for the Exhibition at Philadelphia, United States of America, 1876 (Philadelphia: Gillin & Nagle), Circa 1876 (Box 5)
      - List of Minerals Selected from the Main Collection in the Museum of the Mining School at St. Petersburg, Russia, for the Exhibition at Philadelphia, United States of America, 1876 (Philadelphia: Gillin & Nagle), Circa 1876 (Box 5)
      - Redogörelser för Verldsutsällingen I Filadelfia 1876. Afgifna Till Kongl. Svesska Utställningskomitén. Text. (Stockholm: Central-Tryckeriet), 1877 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous related printed matter
      - Catalogue of a Collection of Books Presented to Alfred T. Goshorn, Director of the International Exhibition of 1876, by the Citizens of Philadelphia, at Independence Hall, May 11, 1877 (Cincinnati: Robert Clarke & Co.), 1878 (Box 5)
      - The Centennial! The Interests of the Great West and the Atlantic-Southern States. Speeches of leading advocates, including those of Ex-Gov. Bigler, of Penna., Ex-Gov. Bradford, of Maryland, the Hon. Frederick Fraley, and others., [ca. 1874] (Box 5)
      - Dassi, G. Philadelphia and Rome (Milan: G. Civelli), 1876 (Box 5)
      - The Empire of Japan. Brief Sketch of the Geography, History and Constitution. Published by the Imperial Commission for the Philadelphia International Exhibition (Philadelphia: William P. Kildare), 1876 (Box 5)
      - Memorial to the Honorable Senate and House of Representatives of the United States, Presented by the Centennial Board of Finance, in Relation to the International Exhibition Held at Fairmount Park, Philadelphia, in 1876 (Philadelphia: Allen, Lane & Scott), 1882 (Box 5)
      - An Outline History of Japanese Education; Prepared for the Philadelphia International Exhibition, 1876, by the Japanese Department of Education (New York: D. Appleton & Co.) (Box 5)
  - Bound Volumes. [Note: the number indicated in the Folder column is the number of the Volume]
    - Catalogue of the Argentine Republic, International Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876. (Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott & Co.) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mineral Map and General Statistics of New South Wales, Australia. (Sydney: Thomas Richards), 1876 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition, 1876. Victoria, Australia. Official Catalogue of Exhibits, Essays, etc. (Melbourne: M'Carron, Bird & Co.) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition, 1876. Special Catalogue of the Austrian Department in Memorial Hall. (Philadelphia: Edward Stern & Co.), [ca. 1876] (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Welthausstellung in Philadelphia 1876. Katalog der Österreichischen Abtheilung. Herausgegben von der Österreichischen Commission für die Weltausstellung in Philadelphia. (Wien), [ca. 1876] (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Exposition Internationale de Philadelphie. Belgique. Catalogue des produits industriels et des oeuvres d'art (Bruxelles), 1876 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Catalogue of the Brazilian Section. Philadelphia International Exhibition, 1876. (Philadelphia: Hallowell & Co.), [ca. 1876] (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Da Camara, J. Ewbank. Chemins de fer de la province de St. Paul Brésil.) Données techniques et statistiques. (Rio de Janeiro: G. Leuzinger & Fils), 1875 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Da Gama, José de Saldanha. Catalogue of the Products of the Brazilian Forests at the International Exhibition in Philadelphia (New York: "O Novo Mundo"), 1876 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Da Gama, José de Saldanha. Notes in Regard to Some Textile Plants in Brazil, the International Exhibition at Philadelphia in 1876 (New York: "O Novo Mundo") (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Moreira, Nicolau Joaquim. Agricultural Instructions for Those Who May Emigrate to Brazil (Rio de Janeiro: Imperial Instituto Artistico), 1875 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Moreira, Nicolau J. U.S. International Exhibition. Historical Notes Concerning the Vegetable Fibres, exhibited by Severino L.da C. Leite (New York: "O Novo Mundo"), 1876 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Moreira, Nicolau J. U.S. Centennial Exhibition. Brazilian Coffee. (New York:"O Novo Mundo"), [ca. 1876] (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Catálogo de la Esposicion Chilena en la Centenario de Filidelfia. (Valparaiso: Imprenta del Mercurio), 1876 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Centennial Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876. Dominion of Canada, Province of Ontario. Catalogue of Exhibits in Education Department. (Toronto: Hunter, Rose & Co.) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hodgins,J. George. Special Report to the Honourable Minister of Education, on the Ontario Educational Exhibit, and the Educational Features of the International Exhibition, at Philadelphia, 1876. (Toronto: Hunter, Rose & Co.), 1877 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - List of Awards to Canadian Exhibitors. International Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876., [ca. 1876] (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Philadelphia International Exhibition, 1876. Descriptive Catalogue of a Collection of Rocks. (Montreal: Lovell Printing and Publishing Co.) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Expositions internationales. Philadelphie, 1876. France. Oeuvres d'art et produits industriels (Paris) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Poirrier, A. Exposition universelle de Philadelphie. Matières colorantes et produits chimiques (Paris: Centrale des chemins de fer), 1876 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Universal Exhibition at Philadelphia in 1876. France. Notices on the Models, Charts and Drawings Relating to the Works of the "Ponts et chaussées" and the Mines Collected by Order of the Ministry of Public Works. (Paris: Government Printing Office) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Deutscher Katalog. German Catalogue. (Berlin), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Hirschwald, August. The Chemical Industry of Germany at the Centennial Exhibition in Philadelphia (Berlin), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Esposizione Universale di Filadelfia 1876. Catalogo degli Espositori Italiani. Publicato per cura del Comitato Centrale (Firenze: Stabilimento Giuseppe Civelli) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - International Exhibition, 1876. Official Catalogue of the Japanese Section, and Descriptive Notes on the Industry and Agriculture of Japan. Published by the Japanese Commission. (Philadelphia) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Philadelphia International Exhibition, 1876. Mexican Section. Special Catalogue and Explanatory Notes. (Philadelphia: Dan. F. Gillin) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Elementary and Middle-Class Instruction in the Nether-lands, and Their Development in Accordance With the Laws of 13th August 1857 (Elementary Instruction) and 2nd May 1863 (Middle-Class Instruction). Published by the Royal Commission of the Netherlands. (Leyden: A.W. Sythoff), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - International Exhibition at Philadelphia 1876. The Dutch Society of Sciences at Harlem. Historical Notice. List of Protectors, Presidents, Secretaries, Directors, Native and Foreign Members. List of Works Published by the Society Since Its Foundation in 1752 Till the 1st of January 1876. (Harlem: De Erven LoosJes) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - International Exhibition, Philadelphia 1876. Special Catalog of the Netherland Section. Edited by Authority of the Royal Commission of the Netherlands. (Amsterdam: C.G. Van der Post), [ca. 1876] (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Van Kerkwyk, L.C. International Exhibition of Articles of Industry, Art, etc. Held at Philadelphia in 1876. A Sketch of the Public Works in the Netherlands (Haarlem: Johannes Enschedé and Sons) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Vereeniging: "De Ambachtsschool," Gevestigd te Rotterdam. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Opgericht in het jaar 1869. Corporation: "The Artisan's School," Rotterdam. Holland. Established in 1869. (Rotterdam: Nijgh & Van Ditmar) [2 copies], undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Norwegian Special Catalogue for the International Exhibition at Philadelphia. 1876. (Christiania: B.M. Bentzen) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sketch of the Orange Free State of South Africa. Issued by the Orange Free State Commission, at the International Exhibition Philadelphia. 1876. (Bloemfontein), 1875 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - International Exhibition, 1876. Philadelphia. Catalogue. Departments I. II. III. IV. V. Mining & Metallurgy. Manufactures. Education and Science. Fine Arts. Machinery., [ca. 1876] (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Portugal. Administração Geral des Matas do Reino. Exposição de Philadelphia (Lisboa: Fornecedores da Casa de Bragança), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Catalogue of the Russian Section. International Exhibition of 1876 at Philadelphia. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - International Exhibition at Philadelphia. Russian Section. Collection of Russian Domestic Manual Labour., 1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - International Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876. Russia. Special Catalogue of Articles Exhibited by the Imperial Russian Mining Department of the Ministry of Crown Domains, at the International Exhibition, at Philadelphia. (Philadelphia: W.A. Church) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Russia. Ministry of War. Pedagogic Museum. Commissary, Professor Heard, Counsellor of the College. (Philadelphia), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Russian Catalogue of the Collections of the Ministry of War. Printed for the Russian Commission. (Philadelphia), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Exposicion Universal de Filadelfia en 1876. Lista Preparatoria del Catalogo de los Expositores de España, y Sus Provincias de Ultramar, Cuba, Puerto Rico y Filipinas. Formada para Uso del Jurado., [ca. 1876] (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Catalogue of the Products Exhibited at the International Exhibition, in Philadelphia, 1876, by the Motala Iron and Steel Works, Sweden, Followed by a Description of the Works, a Price List, and a Map. (Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott & Co.) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Description of Hydrographical and Meteorological Instruments Exhibited by Götheborgs Och Läns Hushallnings Sällskap at the Philadelphia Exhibition 1876, invented by F.L. Ekman, Professor at the Royal Technological Institute in Stockholm. (Stockholm: A.L. Normans Boktryckeri-Aktiebolag) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - The Exhibition of the Geological Survey of Sweden at the Exhibition in Philadelphia 1876. (Stockholm: Kongl. Boktryckeriet, P.A. Norstedt & Söner) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Notices sur la Suède à l'occasion du congrès international des sciences géographiques de 1875, à Paris. (Stockholm: P.A. Norstedt & Söner) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Priskurant från Gustafsbergs Porslinsfabrik (Stockholm: Ivar Haeggströms Boktrycekri), 1874 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sandvik Exhibition of Bessemer Steel, at Philadelphia. 1876., [ca. 1876] (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Surahammars Bruks Aktiebolag. Sverige. (Sweden. Suède. Schweden) Adress Surahannar (Stockholm: Central-Tryckeriet), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Swedish Catalog. International Exhibition, 1876. Philadelphia. (Philadelphia: Hallowell & Co.)
      - I. Statistics, [1876] (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - II. Exhibits, [1876] (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Zander, Gustaf. The Mechanico-Therapeutic Institution in Stockholm. Established in 1865. (Philadelphia: Collins, Printer), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Bericht über die Organisation und des Wirken der Eidgenösischen Polytechnischen Schule in Zürich. (Zürich: Druck von Zürcher und Furrer), 1875 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bericht über Zweck, Gründung, Einrichtung und Frequenz der freiwilligen Fortbildungsschule für Handwerks- und Handels Lehrlinge in St. Gallen und ihre Betheiligung an der internationalen Ausstellung in Philadelphia 1876. (St. Gallen: Joh. Buff), [ca. 1876] (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - General Report Regarding the Swiss Unions of Young Merchants, Their Nature and Development. (Zurich: J. Herzog), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Internationale Ausstellung in Philadelphia 1876. Das Unterrichts-, Schul- und Bildungswesen der Schweizerischen Abteilung. (St. Gallen: Zollikofer'schen Buchdruckerei) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Report of the Object, Foundation, Organization and Attendance of the Voluntary School for the Improvement of Merchants' and Artisans' Apprentices in St. Gall and Its Participation at the International Exhibition at Philadelphia 1876. (St. Gall: J. Buff), [ca. 1876] (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Die Schweizerischen Vereine junger Kaufleute, ihr Wesen und ihre Entwicklung. (Zürich: J. Herzog), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Swiss Catalogue. International Exhibition, 1876, Philadelphia., [ca. 1876] (Box 7, Folder 5)